http://www.actuaries.org.uk/privacy-policy

Who we are
We are the Institute and Faculty of Actuaries (IFoA) and our subsidiaries: Continuous Mortality Investigation (CMI) Limited, ICA 98 Limited, and Institute and Faculty Education (IFE) Limited.  We are the chartered professional body dedicated to educating, developing and regulating actuaries based both in the United Kingdom and internationally
We are registered as Data Controllers with the Information Commissioners Office (ICO) in the United Kingdom:
The IFoA registration number: Z4899224
The CMI Registration number: ZA121735
Where we are based
We maintain offices in England, Scotland, China, Hong Kong and Singapore.
How you can contact us
For general enquiries, visit the contact us page.
For CMI specific enquiries: info@cmilimited.co.uk
For enquiries about this notice or your information rights: our Data Protection Officer can be contacted by:
Telephone: +44 (0) 131 240 1311
Email: data.protection@actuaries.org.uk
Why we need to process your personal data
Who you are:
Why we process your data:
A member of the IFoA
To facilitate your membership of the IFoA and to assist in the fulfilment of our role as a regulator
A member of another actuarial association undertaking IFoA examinations or applying for mutual recognition
To administer the setting of assessments or in considering applications for mutual recognition status
A prospective member of the IFoA or non-member wishing to sit IFoA examinations that are available to non-members
To process your application to join the IFoA.  If you are sitting IFoA assessments independently as a non-member, we need to use your personal data in the course of setting assessments
A non-member attendee or speaker at an IFoA event
To administer your attendance at specific events
A non-member undertaking voluntary work for the IFoA
To support the administrative and communications activity required to manage volunteers
An organisational representative or contact under the IFoA Quality Assurance Scheme (QAS)
In the course of processing your organisation’s application for QAS status and any subsequent administration associated with the QAS.  You can read the QAS privacy notice here
An organisational representative or contact under the IFoA Designated Professional Body Scheme (DPB)
In the course of your organisation’s application for DPB status and any subsequent administration associated with DPB
A customer or supplier of goods or services to the IFoA
To communicate with you, place or fulfil orders for goods or services and to send and receive payments
A job applicant
To assist with the administration of the recruitment and selection process
A member of IFoA staff or someone engaged in a paid role
For the day to day administration of your employment or engagement with us
A user of the IFoA website
To analyse site performance and, if you are a registered user, to provide account related functionality
Someone interested in a career as an Actuary (including school children)
To keep you up to date with relevant information about actuarial careers
Where we get your personal data
Depending on our reasons for processing your data the sources of this data may be:
you;
your current and previous employer(s);
other actuarial organisations;
educational bodies including schools;
other regulators;
employment agencies;
credit reference agencies;
your previous customers or suppliers;
social media and the Internet;
public records.
If you browse our website we may collect basic information about you via Google Analytics. For more information please see our Cookie Policy
The lawful basis for processing your personal data
The IFoA only process personal data where there is a lawful basis for doing so.  These are:
legal obligation;
contract;
vital interest;
legitimate interest;
public task.
In line with our role as a regulator we may also process personal data where there is a substantial public interest.  This means we may process data without consent in order to protect the public from dishonesty, or in the investigation of malpractice, unlawful acts or improper conduct.
The types of personal data we process
Depending on our reasons for processing your data we may process your:
contact details (i.e. name, previous name(s), current and previous postal addresses, work address, email addresses, phone number(s));
marital status;
education history and exam performance;
employment history;
professional interests;
payments (to and from us);
financial details;
correspondence (to and from us);
professional development;
attendance at events;
national insurance number or equivalent;
passport / identity card number;
health information;
location of birth;
criminal records;
disciplinary records.
If you browse our website, we may capture and process:
a unique machine-generated visitor ID;
the date and time of your first visit, current visit, and total number of visits to the site;
the number of pages visited;
when your visit has ended;
information about the traffic source (where you came from).
How we keep your data secure
Personal data received by the IFoA will be held in accordance with our information security standards.  When we share data with third parties we ensure the required technical and organisational controls are in place to keep the data secure.  When sharing personal data we use appropriate controls and safeguards.  These will be specified in our individual Data Sharing agreements.  Examples include only dealing with authorised individuals, adhering to internal policy controls and the use of secure file sharing portals and encryption.
Children's data
From time to time the IFoA processes the personal data of children.  This may be to facilitate entry to IFoA sponsored academic competitions, recognise excellence in mathematics at secondary education level or to keep aspiring actuaries up to date with relevant careers information.  When we do this the lawful basis is our legitimate interests as the chartered body for actuaries in the United Kingdom.  Children's data is kept securely at all times, and available only to those employees that require access to it for their job.
When we share your personal data with third parties
We will share, where appropriate, your personal data with the following organisations:
payment processors and our bank;
exam centres holding exams on our behalf;
organisations assisting with exam logistics such as marking platform providers, scanning services and plagiarism checking;
the British Council;
the times newspaper;
publishers;
other actuarial organisations;
electoral services providers;
travel and accommodation booking service providers;
credit reference agencies;
employment agencies;
your current and/or previous employer;
courier delivery services;
external legal advisors;
third parties who supply the services that support the delivery of our publications, newsletters and electronic library services;
if you're representing us in the UK or overseas and we are funding your travel, we may share  personal data about you with travel services, hotels and selected third parties only to facilitate your travel and attendance;
members and lay-members via involvement in our boards, committees, working parties, member interest groups and regional societies;
members and lay-members acting in roles as principle examiners, exam supervisors, other exam personnel, exam counsellors, independent examiners, subject matter experts, and investigating actuaries;
tracing services, in relation to compliance and disciplinary matters;
Competent authorities - i.e. tribunals, courts, police forces, and other regulators such as the Financial Reporting Council (FRC), the Prudential Regulation Authority (PRA), the Pensions Regulator (tPR), or the Financial Conduct Authority (FCA).
Where we share your personal information with other regulators, this is part of our regulatory function, and extends to disclosures relating to disciplinary actions, as well as periodic auditing of our activity by competent authorities.  In line with our rules and byelaws, we will not seek your consent for these disclosures.
Illustrative examples of data sharing with third parties:
Category of third party recipient
Whose data
Examples of data sharing
Other IFoA members acting on behalf of the IFoA
IFoA members volunteering or applying for volunteer vacancies
To facilitate communication between working parties, committees or boards
Employers of actuaries
IFoA members
For the payment of member fees by their employer
The provision of examination pass and new qualifier lists
Sharing information relating to an identified regulatory concern about an IFoA member
Other actuarial associations
IFoA members,
Members of other actuarial associations, applicants for the CERA mark
Sharing of examination related data for associations using IFoA exam infrastructure
Processing Mutual Recognition Agreement applications
Sharing information about an active investigation in to an IFoA member that is also a member of another society
Sharing information about regulatory responsibilities, framework and enforcement in the public interest for the purpose of membership of the International Actuarial Association and the Actuarial Association of Europe
Universities, colleges and educational providers
Prospective and current student members of the IFoA and other actuarial associations
The validation of information provided in applications to become a student member of the IFoA
The validation of applications for exemption from IFoA professional examinations
Regulators and competent authorities
IFoA members
Sharing information relating to an identified regulatory concern about an IFoA member with whom there is a legitimate shared regulatory public interest, for example, with the FRC, the PRA, the FCA and the tPR.
Sharing information for the purpose of proportionately discharging any legitimate regulatory oversight responsibility
Sharing information about an active investigation in to an IFoA member
Organisations and individuals involved in the assessment and delivery of the examinations of the IFoA
Student members of the IFoA, non-member candidates and members of other actuarial organisations sitting IFoA examinations
Information sent to examination assessment centres to support the delivery of examinations and the accommodation of individual student requirements
Data sent to online assessment platforms
Candidate information shared with the British Council for the purposes of managing examinations arrangements at overseas centres
Exam scripts submitted for plagiarism checks
Data sent to examiners in the process of marking assessments
Suppliers of member related services
IFoA members and non-members that have registered their interest in our qualifications or services
Sharing of data with our email messaging service provider to send informational messages
Sharing lists of qualified actuaries with electoral services providers for the purpose of voting on Honorary Fellows or changes to bye laws
Providing access to our membership system to third party contractors and support services for software development and improvement
Basic information about attendees at IFoA events.  Please note, where events offer catering this may extend to any critical health related information such as allergies or dietary intolerances.
Sharing of information with payment processors
Sharing address and telephone contact details with postal services and couriers for the delivery of materials in hard copy
Where we partner with an external agency to deliver a member survey we’ll share details back and forth if you choose to make yourself available for follow up questions
Publishers and digital content providers
IFoA members and non-member subscribers
Provision of access to online journals and library resources
Employment agencies
Job applicants
In the course of progressing applications for roles at the IFoA
Members of the public making a complaint about an actuary
IFoA members
Where appropriate: sharing information in the course of the investigation of the complaint
Social media
We have separate terms and conditions for our social media channels covering issues around data sharing with channel owners, content and behaviour.  These are available to review here
When we might transfer your information across borders
We avoid transferring your personal information to third countries wherever possible. Where it is not possible to avoid transferring, we include Standard Contract Clauses and other controls in our agreements with our suppliers to ensure appropriate safeguards are in place.
We will only routinely store or process personal data:
within the European Economic Area (EEA); or
within countries recognised by the European Commission (EC) as providing an adequate level of protection; or
outside the EEA or countries recognised as adequate by the EC using standard contract clauses or similar contractual controls.
As an international body, from time to time, in pursuance of our operational objectives and to facilitate the delivery of examination and member related services we may transfer personal data on a periodic basis across jurisdictions.  When we do this we will ensure appropriate technical, organisational and contractual safeguards are in place.
How long we retain your personal data
We only retain personal data for as long as legally required or as long as required by the objects in our Royal Charter.
We securely dispose of personal data when the retention period has expired.
Copies of our Records Retention Schedule can be requested via our Data Protection Officer: data.protection@actuaries.org.uk
When the use of your personal data is based on our legitimate interests
If we send you information based on our legitimate interests as a professional body such as professional newsletters, updates on our activity, Continuous Professional Development opportunities and notices of events you are able to opt out of receiving this at any time.
By Royal Charter, we are obliged to act in the public interest. Pursuant to our role as a regulator and the objects of our Charter you cannot opt-out of receiving certain types of regulatory and governance related information.
Your rights as a data subject
You have the right to:
obtain a copy of any personal data we hold that is about you and not subject to any exemption in data protection law, including footage recorded on Closed Circuit Television (CCTV) systems where the IFoA is the Data Controller;
correct any information we hold about you that is inaccurate or out of date;
ensure we dispose of any personal data we hold about you (once all legal and regulatory record keeping requirements have expired);
restrict the processing your personal data;
object to us processing your personal data;
erase your personal data, where we no longer have a lawful basis or valid operational reason for holding it;
request we send all or some of the personal data we hold about you to another organisation.
If you wish to exercise any of your rights please contact the Data Protection Officer with your request: data.protection@actuaries.org.uk
If you’re unhappy with how we have used your personal data
In the first instance, please contact our Data Protection Officer so that we can deal with your enquiry.  If you are unhappy with how we deal with your concerns you have the right to make a complaint to a Supervisory Authority about how we process your personal data.
In the United Kingdom the Supervisory Authority is the Information Commissioner’s Office
We updated this notice on the 13th November 2020:
We removed references to Privacy Shield in light of recent legal developments
We added information about our use of CCTV
We made it clearer that, from time to time, we collect information about/from children
Filter or search events
Start date
Start date
E.g., 11/12/2020
End date
End date
E.g., 11/12/2020
Search
Who is this event aimed at
- Any -EveryoneStudentsQualified membersTechnical analystThose interested in joining the profession
CPD types
- Any -TechnicalProfessional Skills TrainingEthical learningBusiness skillsMixed
Location
- Any -East EnglandWest EnglandNorth EnglandSouth EnglandMidlandsN. IrelandRepublic of IrelandScotlandWalesInternational
Event type
Practice area
Events calendar
Running off the £2 trillion of UK corporate sector defined benefit liabilities in an efficient and effective fashion is the biggest challenge facing the UK pensions industry. Trustees and sponsors overseeing those schemes need to be clear on their target end-state and the associated journey plan – but too few have well articulated and robust plans.
As the halfway point of his tenure as IFoA President approaches, Tan Suee Chieh would like to invite you to his Presidential Update on 12 January 2021 at 08.30am (UTC).
The Presidential Update will allow Suee Chieh to set out his report card of how the last six months have gone - a period which has seen both the IFoA and the profession go through a significant number of changes at a time of real uncertainty and challenge.
The actuarial skill set has much to offer the banking industry. So many of the skills that actuaries acquire during their working life translate across to the world of banking and yet banking is perceived as an alien environment to many actuaries. But is it?
Guaranteed products evolved to address genuine customer needs and wants.  However, they have fallen from favour in the UK market over time (yet still remain popular in some other countries).
The Long-Term Product Guarantees Working Party was established by the Life Board in 2019 to investigate long term guarantees, traditionally available as pension, investment and annuity products in the UK.
Understanding biases in trustee decision making
What is the evidence that “behavioural” factors, such as human psychology, company culture, corporate politics and conflicts of interest, cause institutional investors to deviate from optimal behaviour? Professor Peter Ayton (Leeds University Business School) presents his findings from the first extensive research programme conducted into the decision making processes of pension fund trustees.
This free-to-view webinar for IFoA members is the first in the IFoA’s 2021 series highlighting its commissioned research through its Actuarial Research Centre (ARC) and offers an opportunity to put questions to the panel on the practical implications for actuaries working in investments and other areas.
Covid-19 has required an urgent and cross-practice initiative to facilitate the extensive impact this pandemic has across all industries. IFoA members have been keen to contribute in a different way, so we developed the IFoA Covid-19 Action Taskforce [ICAT] to coordinate our effort, with a more efficient governance.
We have over 500 volunteers and countless topics which we have amalgamated into 93 workstreams.
Drawing from his most recent book “The New Long Life” and his longevity research Andrew J Scott will outline how longer lives and new technologies will fundamentally reshape how we structure our lives and transform the economy. As well as looking at the agenda this will set governments and corporates he will focus on the implications for you and how you prepare your future career.
